Preliminary Inventory to the George Barr Baker Papers, 1919-1932
Hoover Institution Archives
Geoge Barr Baker Papers,
1919-1932
24000
Baker, George Barr, 1870-1948
14 manuscript boxes (5.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, photographs, and printed matter, relating to the American Relief Administration; Commission for Relief in Belgium; Paris Peace Conference; American presidential politics and the 1924, 1928, and 1932 presidential campaigns; Calvin Coolidge; Herbert Hoover; the Republican Party; and the foreign language press.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Sims, William Sowden, 1858-1936.; Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920)Supreme Economic Council.; Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); Université catholique de Louvain (1835-1969); Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); American Relief Administration.; American Relief Administration. European Children's Fund.; Censorship.; International relief.; Journalism--United States.; Oil industries--Mexico.; Presidents--United States--Election.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.; Belgium.; Mexico.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; National Committee of the United States for the Restoration of the Université of Louvain.; C.R.B. Educational Foundation.
Biography
American journalist; a director of the American Relief Administration.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, photographs, and printed matter, relating to the American Relief Administration; Commission for Relief in Belgium; Paris Peace Conference; American presidential politics and the 1924, 1928, and 1932 presidential campaigns; Calvin Coolidge; Herbert Hoover; the Republican Party; and the foreign language press.
Container List
- Akerson, George (Box 1.)
- Baker, George B.
  - Geneology
  - Diary, 1940 February-July
- Baker, Laura (Mrs. G. Baker)
- Barbour, William T.
- Butler, Nicholas Murray and Sarah
- Butler, Philippi H. (Lou Henry Hoover's Secretary, 1931-1933)
- Buxton, Dorothy F.
- Cahan, Abraham
- Cartier, E. de, Baron (Belgian Ambassador to the United States)
  - 1919-1923
  - 1924-1925
- Chapin, Roy D. (Box 2.)
- Childs, J. Rives
- Coolidge, Calvin - Campaign correspondence (Baker was Publicity Chairman for Coolidge Campaign, 1924). Includes a letter to Baker, 1926 January
- Cosgraves, J. O'Hara
- Crocker, Templeton
- Egan, Martin and Eleanor
  - 1918-1926
  - 1927-1935
- Emerson, Edwin (author of Hoover And His Times)
- Eppley, Marion
- Fertig, August J.
- Fesler, Ruth (Mrs. Robert Lipman, Lou Henry Hoover's Secretary)
- Field, Charles K. (Box 3.)
- Flesh, Edward M.
- Fletcher, Henry P.
- Foreman, Evan Howell - A.R.A. articles, 1919
- Fox, Alan - Campaign speeches for Herbert Hoover, 1931
- Fuller, Parmer and Adeline
- Furubotn, Konrad
- Gest, Morris
- Gibson, Hugh
- Gilchrist, Harry L.
- Goethals, George W., General
- Goode, William A.
- Gutherie, Connop, Sir and Lady Gutherie
- Gutterson, Herbert, "Memorandum On Hoover Strength Among Foreign Nationals," 1928 March 1
- Hall, Mildred
- Hamill, John
- Hard, William N.
- Haskell, William N.
- Hastings, George A.
- Heinecke, G. E.
- Heinz, Howard
- Herter, Christian A., 1922-1932
- Hoover, Herbert C. (and family)
  - 1916-1928. Includes some genealogy
  - 1929-1933
- Joslin, Theodore G.
- Kaufman, S. Jay (Box 4.)
- Keena, Leo
- Kellogg, Vernon
- Keppell, F. D.
- Kernochan, Frederic
- Kilgour, B. L., Jr.
- Klauber, Charles
- Klein, John C.
- Klein, Julius (Assistant Secretary of Commerce, 1932)
- Kleindienst, R. A.
- Kohl, Tracy
- La Guardia, Fiorello H.
- Lancaster, C. B.
- Lane, Gertrude B.
- Leach, Henry Goddard
- Leahy, Lamar P.
- Lee, Ivy L.
- Leicht, Emil
- Leon, Maurice
- Levenson, Melvin
- Lewis, John David
- Lewis, John L.
- Liggett, Walter W.
- Lindbergh, Charles A.
- Lindley, D. Howell
- Logan, James A., Jr. (U.S. Food Administration)
- Lucas, Robert H.
- Lucey, John F.
- Mac Arthur, Mable (Box 5.)
- Mc Curdy, Allen
- Mc Mullin, Dare
- Maier, David
- Marcosson, Isaac F.
- Marks, Diamond, Mrs. (nee Ponsoby)
- Meloney, William Brown, Mrs.
- Mercier, Cardinal
- Merrill, A. Stanton
- Merritt, Ralph P.
- Miller, John Barnes
- Miller, Nathan L.
- Miscellaneous correspondence
- Mundelein, George, Cardinal
- Murphy, Framer and Goodrich (re Eiduk)
- Orlowski, Joseph
- Paderewski, Ignacy
- Page, Frank C.
- Patchin, Robert H.
- Pate, Maurice
- Percy, Eustace, Lord
- Pike, Mary (niece of George Barr Baker)
- Pike, Roy M.
- Poland, W. B.
- Post, Emily Price (Box 6.)
- Pulitzer, Joseph
- Pyne, Percy R.
- Requa, Mark L.
- Richey, Lawrence
- Rick, James J.
- Rickard, Edgar
- Ridgeway, Erman J.
- Robinson, Henry M.
- Rodd, Francis
- Roosevelt, Franklin D.
- Roosevelt, Theodore (son of President Theodore Roosevelt)
- Sawtelle, Raymond H.
- Skinner, Otis
- Sokoloff, Boris
- Stephens, Alice King
- Stettinius, Edward R.
- Stokes, Harold Phelps
- Strothers, French
- Taylor, Lark
- Timberlake, William
- Tuthill, Marshall
- Walden, Dulcie W.
- Walsh, Edmund S. J., Rev.
- White, John Brown
- Wilder, Charles J.
- Wilson, Woodrow. Includes letter to George Creel, 1918 August 20
- Photographs of Lou Henry Hoover's South American trip, 1928 (Box 7.)
- Miscellaneous other photographs
- Two autographed photographs
  - Coolidge to Baker, n.d.
  - Hoover to Baker, n.d.
- Miscellaneous pamphlets, posters, and other printed matter re Herbert Hoover, 1932 (Box 8.)
- American Friends of Poland, Inc. (Box 9.)
- American Relief Administration
  - European Children's Fund (documents on organization)
  - Russian relief papers
  - Miscellany. Includes U.S. Food Administration telegrams
- Associated Negro Press
- Campaign issues
- Censorship
  - 1917-1918
  - 1919 January-February
  - 1919 March
  - 1919 April-May
  - 1919 June-November (Box 10.)
- Central Press Association
- Chase collection of portraits
- Dutch Treat Club, 1924-1934
- Engineer's National Hoover Committee for Re-Election, 1932
- Fortune (article on Hoover's fortune)
- Friends of Belgium
- Friends Service Committee
- Fuel Administration Of New York, 1922-1923 (Box 11.)
- Germany, 1916
- "The Great Fat Fight" by George Barr Baker, The Saturday Evening Post, 1928
- Inside Stuff
- League of Nations
- Louvain University Library
  - 1922-23
  - 1924
  - 1925-1929
- Mexican documents, 1924-1930
- Mexico - Oil, 1920-1927
- Motion pictures, 1919-1929 (Box 12.)
- National Civic Federation, 1923-1932
- National Consumer League, 1926
- Press, Foreign, 1918-1932
- Prohibition, 1932
- Republican clubs
  - 1924-1932
  - 1933-1934
- Sims, William S., Admiral
  - General, 1909-1923
  - Memoirs (partial galley) (Box 13.)
  - Sims-Daniels controversy
- South American trip
  - General
    - 1928
    - 1929
  - Press dispatches
    - A
    - B
- Speeches
- Hoover War library at Stanford (Box 14.)
- Supreme Economic Council
  - 1919 January-June
  - 1919 July-August
- "The Road to Rome." Includes correspondence with Cardinal Gibbons
- The Iron Circle
- War debts, 1922-1932
- White House conference, 1930
- Yosemite, U.S.S. (Gilbert Wilkes camp #17)